If you’re someone who has turned to snacking on junk food more in the pandemic, you’re not alone.
如果你在疫情期间转而更多地拿垃圾食品当零食，那么并不只有你这样。
Investigative reporter Michael Moss says processed food is engineered to hook you, not unlike alcohol, cigarettes, or other harmful substances.
调查记者迈克尔·莫斯说，加工食品经过精心设计，就是为了让你上瘾，这与酒、香烟或其他有害物质不无相似之处。
His 2013 book, Salt Sugar Fat, explored food companies’ aggressive marketing of those products and their impact on our health.
他2013年的著作《盐糖脂》探讨了食品公司对这些产品的强势营销，以及这些产品对我们健康的影响。
In his new book, Hooked, Moss updates the food giants’ efforts to keep us eating what they serve, and how they’re responding to complaints from consumers and health advocates.
在新书《上瘾》中，莫斯更新了对食品巨头的记述：它们为了让我们一直吃自家供应的食物做了哪些努力，又是如何回应消费者和健康倡导者的不满与批评的。
Processed food is inexpensive, it’s legal, and it’s everywhere.
加工食品价格低廉、合法，而且随处可见。
Companies’ advertising is cueing us to remember those products and we want those products constantly.
各家公司的广告在唤起我们对这些产品的记忆，而我们无时无刻不想要这些产品。
So the food environment is one of those key things that make food even more problematic for so many people.
所以，食物之所以对这么多人来说更加成问题，食物环境就是关键原因之一。
Memory, nostalgia in particular, plays a big role in the foods we crave.
记忆，尤其是怀旧之情，对我们渴望吃哪些食物起着很大的作用。
Soda companies discovered that if they put a soda in the hands of a child when they’re at a ball game with their parents, that soda will forever be associated with that joyous moment.
汽水公司发现，如果在孩子跟父母一起看球赛时把一瓶汽水放到孩子手中，那么这种汽水就会永远与那个欢乐的时刻联系在一起。
Later in life, when that child wants to experience a joyous moment, they’re going to think of soda.
日后，这个孩子想体验欢乐时刻时，就会想到汽水。
Many people seek comfort in the snacks they remember from childhood.
许多人会从自己儿时记忆中的零食里寻求慰藉。
Moss examines the way companies capitalize on our memories, cravings and brain chemistry to keep us snacking.
莫斯考察了各家公司如何利用我们的记忆、渴望和大脑化学机制，让我们不停地吃零食。
One of the reasons Moss came to think that some of these food products are even more powerful, more troublesome than drugs can be is memory.
莫斯之所以逐渐认为其中一些食品甚至比毒品威力更大、更难对付，原因之一就是记忆。
What we eat is all about memory.
我们吃什么，全在于记忆。
And we begin forming memories for food at a really early age.
而且，我们在很小的时候就开始形成对食物的记忆。
And we keep those memories for a lifetime.
我们还会终生保留这些记忆。
Knowing this, the food industry spends lots of time trying to shape the memories that we have for its products.
食品行业深知这一点，所以花大量时间设法塑造我们对其产品的记忆。
One of the features of addiction that scientists studying drug addiction discovered back in the 1990s was that the faster a substance hits the brain, the more apt we are as a result to act impulsively.
研究毒瘾的科学家早在20世纪90年代就发现，成瘾的特征之一是：一种物质作用于大脑的速度越快，我们就越容易因此冲动行事。
There’s nothing faster than food in its ability to hit the brain.
没有什么能比食物更快地作用于大脑。
For Moss, this puts the notion of “fast food” in an entirely new light as this isn’t limited to fast food chains—almost 90% of food products in grocery stores are processed foods.
在莫斯看来，这让人们以全新的眼光看待“快餐”这一概念，因为这种情况并不仅限于快餐连锁店——超市里近90%的食品都是加工食品。
Everything in the industry is about speed, from manufacturing to packaging.
这个行业里的一切都讲求速度，从生产到包装，无不如此。
Overall, Moss outlines the industry’s dependence on making its products inexpensive, super delicious, and incredibly convenient for consumers.
总的来说，莫斯概述了这个行业对以下做法的依赖：让自家产品价格低廉、超级美味，而且对消费者来说极其方便。
Now that more and more people care about what they put in their bodies and are wanting to eat healthier, these companies are finding it really difficult to meet that new demand because of their own addiction to making these convenience foods.
如今越来越多的人在意自己吃进身体里的东西，想吃得更健康，这些公司却发现实在很难满足这一新需求，因为它们自己对生产这些方便食品上了瘾。